(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T05:34:09.885666",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
I won't let the romance scandal get away, I'll make it disappear.
シル・ヴ・プレジデント
S'il vous président!
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら 人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします
Oath! If I become president, I'll banish any woman who flirts with another's man!
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら いやただの友達だよって誤魔化す奴はヘソから電気を流します
Oath! If I become president, I'll shock anyone who makes excuses saying 'We're just friends!'
だ・だ・だ・大胆不敵 セーショナルクローズアップ
D-D-D-Da-Darling fearless! Sensational close-up!
ド・ド・ド・Don't cry
D-D-D-Don't cry,
やるぜ徹底的にリサーチだ
I'll do a thorough search!
大嫌い? しょうがない? クズは病気ね バイバイ・バイ
Hate it? Can't help it? Scum is a disease, bye-bye, bye.
権力! 財産! 地位名誉!! なににもないけど裁きたいでしょ?
Power! Wealth! Status, prestige!! You want to judge me for nothing, don't you?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね まずは君を捕まえるね
D-D-D-When I become president, I'll catch you first.
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせるね (だ・だ・だ!)
With a wet towel, I'll make you confess everything (D-D-D!)
誰ですか あの女(いやぁ~) ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
Who is that woman? (Oh my~) I won't let the romance scandal get away, I'll make it disappear.
でしょ?
Right?
シル・ヴ・プレプレプレジデント
S'il vous ple-ple-ple-president
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら ただの仕事の付き合いだよって言う奴は二度と働けなくしてあります
Oath! If I become president, I'll ensure anyone who says 'It's just work' will never work again.
宣誓! 以下略! いや向こうが強引でさ〜っていう男の口にはレジンを流し込んで固めてやります!
Oath! The rest is omitted! If a guy says 'She was too pushy~', I'll pour resin in his mouth and harden it!
み・み・み・密着 まるでドン・ファン気取りスキャンダラス
Close, close, close, close! He's like Don Juan, scandalous!
ま・ま・ま・末端価格 甲斐性なしのスクープね
Base price, scoop of a man with no ability.
愛はない? 理由じゃない 悪くないのね はいはいはい
No love? That's not a reason, not bad, right? Yes, yes, yes.
おいわない 美優じゃない 悪くないのね はいはいはい
Not saying it, not Mi-yu, not bad, right? Yes, yes, yes.
軽薄! のうのう! いけしゃあしゃあ!!
Frivolous! Shameless! How brazen!!
だ・だ・だ・大統領になってもね 多分君は変わらないね
D-D-D-Even if I become president, you probably won't change.
しらーっとぼけて のらりくらりかわすのね(で・で・で!)
Playing dumb and dodging smoothly (D-D-D!)
でぇーですかっ こんばんは(おわぁ〜!)
How are you? Good evening (Oh wow~!)
本気ですか そうですか(ほらぁ〜!)
Are you serious? Is that so? (Look here~!)
情熱とは不注意 微熱も消してしまいたい
Passion is carelessness, I'd even extinguish a slight fever.
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね マジで君を捕まえるね
D-D-D-When I become president, I'll catch you for real.
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせるね(で・で・で!)
With a wet towel, I'll make you confess everything (D-D-D!)
どこですか 今晩は(おやぁ〜?)
Where are you tonight? (Oh my?)
みっけちゃった バレちゃった(おらぁー!)
Found you, caught you! (Hey!)
夜道にはご用心 さよなら代わりに銃声
Beware of the night, gunshots instead of goodbye.
しる・ヴ・ぷれぷれプレジデント
S'il vous ple-ple-president
ちょっと みんなわき見てんじゃないでしょうね? ちゃんと見ててよね!
Hey, you guys aren't looking away, are you? Make sure you're watching!
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね まじで君を捕まえるね
D-D-D-When I become president, I'll catch you for real.
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせるね(ね・ね・ね!)
With a wet towel, I'll make you confess everything (Ne-ne-ne!)
あら一山 引っ掛けるね
Catching a big haul.
どこですか 今あんた 日にけっちゃった ばれちゃった
Where are you right now? Got tanned, got exposed.
夜道には今夜 人生さようなら
Tonight on the dark road, goodbye to life.
代わりに銃声 シル・ヴ・プレプレプレジデント
Gunshots instead, S'il vous ple-ple-ple-president
シル・ヴ・プレジデント
S'il vous président!
はーい、というわけで！みんな見えてますかー？
Hi everyone! So, can everyone see me?
今日は紫シオン3周年ということで、えーっと...息が切れてるんだけど...
Today is Murasaki Shion's 3rd anniversary, so, um... I'm already running out of breath...
今日は紫シオン3周年ということでね、えー、いっぱい歌ってお喋りして、ゲストの方も...
Today is Murasaki Shion's 3rd anniversary, so we'll sing a lot, chat, and there are guests...
ぜひみんな楽しみに、楽しんでみてください！いぇーい！
Please look forward to it and enjoy yourselves! Yay!
というわけで、次の曲、いきます！
And with that, let's go to the next song!
みんないっぱいツイートしてね！
Everyone, tweet a lot, okay!
素晴らしい世界に今日も乾杯
A toast to this wonderful world today as well
街に飛び交う笑い声も
Even the laughter flying around the town
見て見ぬふりしてるだけの作りのもんさ
Are just fabricated things I turn a blind eye to
気触れそうだ
It's driving me mad
クラクラするほどの良い匂いが
A sweet scent so dizzying
ツンと刺した鼻の奥
Pierced straight through the back of my nose
目を覚ます本能のまま
Following the instincts that awaken my eyes
今日は誰の番だ
Whose turn is it today?
この世界で何ができるのか
What can I do in this world?
僕には何ができるのか
What can I do?
ただその真っ黒な目から涙こぼれ落ちないように
Just making sure tears don't overflow from those pitch-black eyes
願う未来に何度でもずっと喰らいつく
I'll keep biting into the future I wish for, no matter how many times
この間違いだらけの世界の中で君には笑ってほしいから
In this world full of mistakes, I want you to keep smiling
もう誰も傷付けない強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become stronger and stronger so I won't hurt anyone anymore
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can stay as myself
素晴らしい世界は今日も安泰
This wonderful world is peaceful today as well
街に渦巻く悪い話も
Even the bad rumors swirling around the town
知らない知らないふりして目を逸らした
I turned a blind eye, pretending not to know
正気の沙汰じゃないな
This isn't the work of a sane mind
真面目に着飾った行進
A procession dressed up so seriously
鳴らす足音が弾む行き先は
Where are the bouncing footsteps heading?
消えない消えない味が染み付いている裏側の世界
The underside of the world stained with an unforgettable taste
清く正しく生きること 誰も悲しませずに生きること
Living purely and righteously, living without making anyone sad
はみ出さず真っ直ぐに生きること それが間違いじゃないで生きること
Living straight without sticking out, living as if that's not a mistake
ありのまま生きることが正義か 騙し騙し生きるのは正義か
Is living as you are justice? Is living by deceit justice?
僕の有るべき姿とはなんだ 本当の僕は化け物なんだ
What is my proper form? The real me is a monster
教えてくれよ
Tell me
今日も答えのない世界の中であがっているんだよ
Today too, I'm struggling inside a world without answers
不器用だけれど いつまでももう君とただ笑っていたいから
Though clumsy, I just want to keep smiling with you forever
疼く心臓が身体揺らし叫ぶんだよ 今こそ動き出せ
My throbbing heart shakes my body and shouts, "Move now!"
弱い自分を何度もずっと喰らいつく
Biting into my weak self over and over
この間違いだらけの世界の中で君には笑ってほしいから
In this world full of mistakes, I want you to smile
もう誰も泣かせない強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become stronger and stronger so I won't make anyone cry anymore
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can stay as myself
ただ君を護るそのために走る走る走るんだよ
Running, running, running just to protect you
僕の中の僕を越えて
Surpassing the me inside of me
はーい、というわけで！2曲目は怪物でしたー！
Hi! So, the second song was "Monster"!
ちょっとね、可愛い曲からのカッコいい曲ということで、ちょっとね、音の差が激しいかなと思いますが
From a cute song to a cool song, so the difference in tone is pretty big, I think, but...
えー、ほんとにありがとうございますみんな！
Um, thank you so much everyone!
どうでしたか？みんなのコメント見えてるよ、ちゃんと。かっこいいだって、嬉しい！
How was it? I can see everyone's comments properly. "So cool," you say? I'm so happy!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
めちゃ緊張してる、めちゃ緊張してるよ、バカたれが！
I'm so nervous, I'm so nervous, you idiots!
はい、というわけでですね、次 は...あの...ここからはなんと、スペシャルゲストとつまっち...
So, next is... um... from here on, we have a special guest tsuma...
いくよー
Here we go!
はい、というわけでえー
Alright, so, um...
え、先ほどね、え、掛け声をした通りスペシャルゲスト突撃待ちとなっております。
As I just shouted out earlier, we are waiting for a special guest call-in!
お気づきの通り、なんと背景がのライブの素晴らしいステージからなんと真っ黒の真っ黒の深海みたいな背景になっちゃったんですが、ブルーバックということで、
As you may have noticed, the background has changed from that amazing live stage to something like a pitch-black deep sea. Well, it's a blue-back screen, so...
今から紫音の3周年を祝いに3人のホロメンが突撃をしてくれるそうです。
Apparently, three Hololivers are going to call in to celebrate Shion's 3rd anniversary!
え、誰だろうね、みんな。誰だろうね、え、知らないよね、みんなね。そうだよよね、あの告知のサムネにもねちょっとシルエットだけ載せたけど、わかんない。誰だー！
Who could they be, everyone? Who could it be? You don't know, do you? Right, because in the announcement thumbnail, we only posted silhouettes, so you have no idea. Who is it?!
というわけでなんとみんなそれぞれ紫音のために背景を変えてきてくれたそうなので、その背景をベースにポーズを取るのでみんなたくさんスクショしてください。
So, apparently, each of them changed the background specifically for Shion, so we'll be posing based on those backgrounds, everyone, please take lots of screenshots!
ということで衣装もね、あの、通常衣装でやっていこうかなと思います。みんなたくさんみんながたくさんカメラマンになってお写真を撮るという、
So we'll be doing this in our regular outfits. It's a wonderful corner where everyone becomes a photographer and takes pictures!
えー、そんな素敵なコーナーとなっております。ちなみに紫音はまだみんながどんな背景を変えてきてくれたか知らないんだよ、見てないんだよ。だからちょっとねドキドキしております。
By the way, Shion doesn't know what kind of background everyone brought yet, haven't seen it yet. So I'm a little nervous and excited.
というわけでですね、早速1人目の突撃が、突撃突撃が来たそうなので繋いでみましょう！ドキドキ！
So with that, it seems the first guest call-in has arrived, so let's connect! Doki doki!
はーい！
Hii!
あー！どもー！
Ah! Hello there!
この声は…しお先輩！
This voice... Shion-senpai!
るしあちゃん、3周年おめでとう！
Rushia-chan, happy 3rd anniversary!
ありがとう！見えてる？るしあちゃんにも見えてる？
Thank you! Can you see it? Can Rushia-chan see it too?
見えてる見えてる！めっちゃかっこよかったよ！やった！ありがとう！
I can see it, I can see it! It was super cool! Yay! Thank you!
来てくれてありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you for coming! Congratulations!
おめでとう！どうも潤羽るしあです。
Congratulations! Hello, I am Uruha Rushia.
自己紹介。
Self-introduction.
え、え、うん、え、え、今日ね、え、るしあちゃん、背景どんなのだと思う？
Um, um, yeah, um, um, today, um, Rushia-chan, what kind of background do you think I have?
えー、さすがにるしあちゃん可愛いからさ、ね。大好きなんだよね、るしあことの。
Eh, as expected, Rushia-chan is cute, so, you know. I really love Rushia-to-no...
おら！見てるの？実はこっそりね、こっそりこっそり見てるんだけど、もっと可愛いから。
Hey! Are you watching? Actually, secretly, secretly, I've been watching, but it's even cuter.
私突撃してきてほしいちょうだい。突撃ちょ、ちょっとね、
I want you to call in... Please call in, wait, um...
あの、ちょっとね、ここでしお先輩にるしあが用意したね、背景見てほしいと思うんだけど、ちょっと見てよ。え、見る？どろん！
Um, um, here, I want Shion-senpai to see the background I prepared, so please take a look. Eh, look at it? Doron!
ちょ、
Wait,
るしあちゃんさ、ちょっと待って。絵変わってるんだけど！何これ？
Rushia-chan, wait a minute. The picture changed! What is this?
ちょ、るしちゃん、ちょっと待って。絵画の、ちょっと絵、え、何ここさ、絵画があるのね？
Wait, Rushia-chan, wait a minute. A painting, wait, a picture, eh, what, is there a painting here?
ちょっと、るしちゃんちょっと絵隠して。これ、すごいね、るしちゃん見て！
Wait, Rushia-chan, hide the painting a bit. This is amazing, Rushia-chan, look!
ひといいるよ！ちょっと待って！スイカ！
There are people! Wait a minute! Watermelon!
え、これ何、これ？木？あ、え、これさ、これ何だと思う、しお先輩？
Eh, what is this, this? A tree? Ah, eh, what do you think this is, Shion-senpai?
え、わかった！わかった！わかった！これ持つんじゃないの？こうやって。違う？
Ah, I get it! I get it! I get it! You're supposed to hold this, right? Like this. Am I wrong?
そうよ、そうよ！
That's right, that's right!
でかっ！ねえ、でかっ！ねえ、待って、でかっ！これ同じぐらいだよね、るしあちゃん。
So big! Hey, so big! Hey, wait, so big! It's about the same size as you, Rushia-chan.
いや、マジでしお先輩のさ、これ可愛いから。あ、わかった！このスイカ野郎！スイカ野郎をぶっ叩くってことね？
No, seriously, Shion-senpai's... this is cute. Ah, I know! This watermelon bastard! You're going to bash the watermelon bastard, right?
そうそうそう！
Exactly, exactly!
あ、なるほど。あ、ちょっと待って。その前のやつは、ダメ、スイカ切るから、後ろの、あ、これ違うのよ。
Ah, I see. Ah, wait a minute. The one before that, no, because we're cutting the watermelon, the one in the back, ah, that's different.
それ違うのかよ！
That's different?!
それ違うの！
That's different!
あ、これを、こうね、割っちゃうから。
Ah, you're going to split this, like this, by smashing it.
えいって、なんかこう、そういうショット撮ってほしい、
Like "Ei!", I want you to take a shot like that,
え、どう、どう？いい感じ？見て。
Eh, how is it? Does it look good? Look.
あ、いい感じ、いい感じ！めちゃえでかいけど！
Ah, looks good, looks good! Though it's super huge!
めちゃいい感じ！絵がでっけよ！ちょっと海女っぽくして、しお先輩、海女を、海女っぽくして。
Super good! The drawing is huge! Make it a bit like an ama (female diver), Shion-senpai, make it look like an ama diver.
海女なんだ？
An ama diver?
うん。
Yeah.
セクシー。ちょっと、どう、るしあちゃん。
Sexy. So, how is it, Rushia-chan?
あ、ちょっとそこリュックサックあんだ、でっけえの。
Ah, there's a backpack there, a huge one.
おっ！これちょっと面白くて、
Oh! This is kind of funny,
そう、あ、いいね、かわいいかわいい！かわいい！かわいい！ダイナマイトボディが
Yeah, ah, nice, cute, cute! Cute! Cute! A dynamite body...
え？え、あ、え？あ、じゃあもうもっともらって、ちょっとスクショタイム。
Eh? Eh, ah, eh? Ah, then give me more, let's take a screenshot time.
撮ってよー！
Take it!
あ、かわいいね。カシャカシャ！いいよ、いいよ、いいよ、いいよ！カシャカシャの感じがかわいい！
Ah, cute. Click-click! Good, good, good, good! The clicking sound is cute!
じゃあ、ちょっと海も泳いでみよう。海泳ぐわ。
Well, let's try swimming in the sea too. I'll swim in the sea.
行け行け、行け！スイカ追うな、追うな！
Go go, go! Don't chase the watermelon, don't chase it!
海泳ぐ！海泳ぐ！奥にキッズいる、奥にキッズ！
Swimming in the sea! Swimming in the sea! There are kids in the back, kids in the back!
ちょっと待て、混ざってんなキッズ！おい、おい、キッズ！
Wait a minute, kids are mixed in! Hey, hey, kids!
キッズ！海女ね、海女ね！
Kids! Ama diver, right, ama diver!
どう、いい感じだった？
How was it, did it look good?
めちゃかわいい！え、も、もっと、
Super cute! Eh, more, more...
いや、あの、海女をちょっとアップってできないのかな？あ、確かに、アップできるのかな？
No, um, can't we zoom in a bit on the ama diver? Ah, true, can we zoom in?
どうなんだろう、近づけ、近づけないのかな？
I wonder how it is, can we get closer?
あ！あ、いいじゃん！これじゃん！
Ah! Ah, nice! This is it!
それだよ、それだよ！
That's it, that's it!
それだ！あ、これじゃん！それだ！あ、いいじゃん、かわいい！
That's it! Ah, this is it! That's it! Ah, nice, cute!
セクシー。あ、セクシーセクシー、あ、いいね！
Sexy. Ah, sexy sexy, ah, nice!
あ、いい、いいもの見ものだわ。キッズいじめてくるわ。
Ah, nice view. I'm going to go tease the kids.
キッズ！キッズ！
Kids! Kids!
やったよー！
I did it!
イカすし？
Pretty cool, right?
よってきてよってきて
Come closer, come closer!
やったやった、やっつけた！
Yay, I defeated them!
よかったー
I'm so glad!
そう！イイね、ほら後ろにさ
Yeah! It's nice, look in the back,
サーフィン乗ってる人いるんだよ
there's someone surfing back there.
え、本当にこれサーフィンじゃなくね？
Wait, is this really even surfing?
え、サーフィンなんだよ
Wait, it is surfing!
えこれなんかタイヤ付いてるからこれ本当、スノーボードとかじゃない、スケボーとかじゃないこれ！
Wait, it has tires on it, this isn't snowboarding or skateboarding!
最新式のさ、そう、あの海のさ
It's the latest style... yeah, in the ocean...
サーフィンね
Surfing...
最近のサーフィン、タイヤ付いてるやん
Modern surfing has tires now!
どうだろ、うまく取れたかな？みんなどう？
How was it? Did I get it? Everyone, how is it?
なんて言ってる？かわいいからね
What are they saying? "Because it's cute," right?
スケボーじゃね？って言ってるよるせちゃん
Yuruse-chan is saying "Isn't that a skateboard?"
おかしいな
That's weird...
えでもそろそろね、うまく取れたんじゃないかな？ルシアは
But hey, wouldn't you say I got it right? Rushia is...
うん、ありがとう
Yeah, thank you!
退散しようかな？え、本当しゅんぱい
Should I leave now? Ah, seriously, I'm sad.
おめでとう、3周年！ありがとう
Congratulations on 3 years! Thank you!
また遊ぼうね！いっぱい遊ぼうね！バイバーイ！
Let's play again! Let's play lots! Bye-bye!
ありがとう！うん、お姉ちゃんも頑張ってね！はーい！
Thank you! Yep, big sis, do your best too! Okay!
というわけでルシアちゃんでした
So that was Rushia-chan!
これ頑張ってさ、いらすとやでさ、素材集めてさ、ねえ、頑張ってくれたって考えると心が温まりますねこれ
When you think about her working hard to gather assets from Irasutoya, it warms your heart, doesn't it?
というわけで、ダイナマイトボディのシオンでした。どうですかみんな、写真取れたかな？
So that was Dynamite Body Shion. How was it everyone, were you able to take a picture?
というわけでですね、次の方の準備が満タンということで、早速凸をかけていきたいと思います
That being said, since the next person is fully prepared, I'd like to call them right away!
えー、次の方は、こちらです！ドドン
Urrgh, the next person is right here! Ta-da!
マグマ、マグマ、おかゆー！
Magma, magma, Okayu!
シオン3周年おめでとうございます
Shion, congratulations on your 3rd anniversary!
おかゆ、位置情報更新の
Okayu, update your location...
え、待って、おかゆさ、今日さ、ウェディング、ウェディング結婚式とかじゃないの、背景
Wait, Okayu, is today's background not like a wedding, a wedding ceremony?
あ、すごい！よく分かったね、それは
Oh, wow! You figured that out really well, huh?
そう、シオンと結婚式はあげるわけにはいかないっていうとこちょっと用意したからね
Yeah, because we couldn't actually have a wedding with Shion, I prepared that place a bit!
じゃあ僕が用意した背景は、こちらです
Well then, the background I prepared is this one!
え？おかゆ？おかゆ？ちょっと待って、え？
Eh? Okayu? Okayu? Wait a second, eh?
うわぁーん、出してよー！！！
Waaaaah, let me out!!!
でもほら、見て、あ、ありがとう！
But look, see? Ah, thanks!
おかゆはさ、こういうところで結婚式挙げたいっていうこと？
Is Okayu saying she wants to hold a wedding ceremony in a place like this?
まー、シオンと挙げるならここかなあ
Well... if I'm having it with Shion, I guess it's here.
え、本当に行ってる？本当のやつそれ
Wait, are you serious? Is that for real?
いや僕がシオンに嘘なんか付いてるわけないでしょ
I mean, there's no way I'd lie to Shion, right?
うわーん、出してよー！
Waaah, let me out!
まあまあまあ、これなんかねプリクラっぽくてさ
Well, well, this kind of looks like a purikura,
あ、かわいい！かわいい！
Ah, cute! Cute!
かわいい、もっと近づいて、もっと、もっともっと、もっと近づいて！
Cute, get closer, more, even more, get closer!
めっちゃめっちゃかわいいよ、シオン
You're super, super cute, Shion!
もっといけるのかな、いけないのかな
Can we get closer, or can we not?
これがマックスなんかな
Is this the max?
僕マックスかも
I might be at max.
いや、かわいい、なんかピンプリみたいでかわいいよ
Aw, cute, it's cute like a pin-purikura!
いや、なんか悲しくなってきたけどさ、心が寂しくなってきて、おかゆ
But, I'm starting to feel kind of sad, my heart's feeling lonely, Okayu.
でもほら、愛愛傘見てごらん
But hey, look at the love umbrella.
あ、ほら！
Ah, look!
おかゆ、しお、あ、かわいい！しお、おかゆ！
Okayu, Shio, ah, cute! Shio, Okayu!
めちゃくちゃかわいい、しお
So damn cute, Shio!
猫いるじゃん、ここに
There's a cat right here.
あ、おかゆ、これおかゆ？
Ah, Okayu, is this Okayu?
よしよし、そうか、これ僕だよ
There, there, that's right, that's me!
優秀優秀、かわいい
Good job, good job, cute!
しおのさ、悲しい顔を見せてよ、悲しい顔
Shio, show me a sad face, a sad face!
え、悲しい顔いくよ
Eh, I'll do a sad face!
えー、泣いてる？
Eh, are you crying?
えー、かわいい！出して、ここから出して！
Eh, cute! Let me out, let me out of here!
てか結婚式なんだよね、おかゆ、なんで泣かすの？
I mean, it's a wedding, Okayu, why are you making me cry?
感動して泣いちゃったってことね
You cried because you were moved, right?
そう、そういうことだよ
Yeah, exactly!
おかゆ、いや、かわいいな
Okayu... man, you're cute.
ああ、よかった、え、じゃあ今日結婚ってことね、これ
Ah, great, so today means we're getting married, right?
自身、そうだよ
Myself? Yeah, that's right.
本当？やっぱこういうとこがいいじゃん
Really? See, a place like this is nice!
いやいや、ほら天気もいいからさ、なんか窓から光差してるしさ
No no, hey, the weather's nice, and light is shining through the window,
スポットライトみたいだね、ほら、これ
it's like a spotlight, look at this!
そう、シオンはやっぱりね、僕たちのアイドルだからさ
Yeah, Shion is still our idol, after all!
そうね、そうね、そう、いつまでもこういうね
That's right, yeah, always in a place like this...
いつまでもここに、こういうところにいてほしいってこと？おかゆは
You want me to stay here in a place like this forever, Okayu?
え、そういう感じね
Ah, is that how it is?
いやいや、でもさ、好きな子はさ、自分だけのものにしたいっていう気持ち分かるでしょ？
No no, but you know, don't you understand the feeling of wanting the one you like to be only yours?
だったらもう、もう喜んでここにいるよ、おかゆ、じゃあ結婚しようね！
Then I'll gladly stay here, Okayu, let's get married then!
よかったね、ここ。うん、よかった
I'm glad. Yep, I'm glad.
待ってるからね、来てくれるの、隣に。隣にね
I'll be waiting, for you to come to my side. Right next to me.
いや、たまにはね、シオンにこういうね、なんか脱獄ライフを味わってほしかったんだよね
Well, sometimes I wanted Shion to experience this kind of prison escape life.
本当に？
Really?
したことないでしょ
You've never done it, right?
ないよ！ででも、かぐやあるじゃん、そういえば
I haven't! But wait, Kaguya is there, come to think of it.
僕はもうしょっちゅうだよ、牢屋にぶち込まれることなんて
I'm thrown into jail all the time, you know.
ええ、じゃあ今度は一緒にいろ...
Eh, then next time together...
うわぁ～ん！出してよ～！！
Waaah! Let me out!!
一緒にね？
Together, right?
一緒にいこね、お前待ってかんね？
Let's go together, you're gonna wait for me, right?
ありがと、おや、まじかわいいよ！
Thank you, aw, seriously, you're so cute!
ありがと、わかゆ～！
Thank you, Wakayu～!
じゃあ次を、うん。
So, next, yep.
がんばってね続きもね、まだまだね！
Do your best on the rest too, keep it up!
ね、うたちゃんめっちゃ可愛かったかもね、やった！ありがと～わかゆ～！
Uta-chan was super cute, wasn't she? Yay! Thank you, Wakayu～!
バイバ～イ！またね～！
Bye-bye! See you again!
結構こういうとこがね、お前が好きならそれは別にね構わんのだけども、ここでも全然ね？
Pretty much, places like this, if you like it, I don't really mind, even here, completely fine?
なんだけどちょっと寂しいよね、これが結婚式ってなるとね、ちょっと寂し、孤独は感じるよね。
But it's kind of lonely, right? When it comes to a wedding, it feels a bit lonely and isolated.
はい、というわけで、おゆちゃんありがとうございました！
Right, so anyway, Oyu-chan, thank you very much!
次が最後ですね、最後はこの方です。どうぞ！
Next is the last one. Finally, it's this person. Here you go!
ちょっとどういうことなんですか？
Wait, what is the meaning of this?
ちょっと？
Wait?
あくあー！
Aquaー!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
あ、でた！
Ah, it came out!
でたそれ、え、今日誕生日よ！
That came out, eh, today is your birthday!
おめでとう！もう三年目の誕生日ってことでね、そう、でもちょっとさ、許されないけど、どうようなことさっきのずっと聞いてましたけども
Happy birthday! It's your 3rd year birthday, you know, yeah, but wait, you can't forgive that, what do you mean, I was listening to the whole thing earlier...
あくあとお前とは結婚したからさよ。
Because you and Aqua got married.
いやいやいや！お前はあんなところで結婚式上げたいんだって！
No no no! You said you want to hold a wedding ceremony in a place like that!
え、そうやってるだまされてるよ、しおんちゃん、じゃあどんまい！どんまいあくあ！
Eh, you're being fooled, Shion-chan, well then, too bad! Too bad, Aqua!
あくあはあそこが好きなんだよ、あそこで結婚式、私の理想だよって聞いてたもん。
Aqua likes that place, I heard her say she wants her wedding there, that's my ideal.
あ、そうなの？どんまい、どんまいあくあ、いやね、ちょっとねそんなかわいそうなしおんちゃんに今日は
Ah, is that so? Too bad, too bad Aqua, well, today for such a pitiful Shion-chan,
ちょっと私がね、ちょっと用意してきたの、あのね、しおんちゃんさ、プリクラとかさ、行ったことある？
I prepared something, um, Shion-chan, have you ever been to a purikura?
あんまりないよ
Not really
博士の私からすると、今回は、
From me, a doctor, this time,
すっごい、もしかして、寂しいって言ってたから、私がその寂しさをちゃんと埋めてあげるから、ほんと？
Super, perhaps, since you said you were lonely, I'll properly fill that loneliness for you, really?
うん！じゃあね、私が用意した背景、どうぞ！
Yeah! Well then, the background I prepared, here you go!
チャリで来た。超えー！
Came by bicycle. Super!
えっ！しおんちゃん！ねえこれ誰！
Eh! Shion-chan! Hey, who is this?!
やっぱり、やっぱネットの、やっぱプリクラっていう文化の中で、やっぱ一番イニシエの、
After all, in the internet culture of purikura, the most ancient ones,
イニシエの、やっぱ、こう、イニシエから伝わる、こう伝説の、やっぱプリクラっていうのがあって、「チャリで来た」っていうやつなんだけど、
from ancient times, there's this legendary purikura called "Came by bicycle,"
しおんちゃん、これポーズがあって、えっとね、右手をこう前に、この、この人たちと同じように、こう、グーで。さあ、で、ちょっと、ちょっと斜めになって、ちょっと斜め前で、
Shion-chan, there's a pose for this, um, right hand forward, like these people, with a fist. Now, and a bit slanted, a bit slanted forward,
ちょっと、体を斜めに向ける感じ。あ、そうそうそう！そんな感じ！
A bit, body angled diagonally. Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah! Like that!
あ、いいじゃん！いい、ちゃんと撮った？ねえ、みんな撮った？これ完成？
Oh, nice! Nice, did you take it properly? Hey, everyone take it? Is this complete?
え, そう, どう, しおんちゃん? これ誰, これ誰これ?
Eh, yeah, how is it, Shion-chan? Who is this, who is this?
え、これ友達？ねえ、しおんちゃんの友達？
Eh, are these friends? Hey, Shion-chan's friends?
これ、女の子だよよね？
This is a girl, right?
女の子だよ！本当だ、本当だ！女の子だよ！
It's a girl! Really, really! It's a girl!
あ、そう、やっぱね、しおんちゃんは3周年ってことでね、やっぱ幸せになってほしいから、そこって友達いっぱい用意したよ。
Ah, right, since Shion-chan is celebrating her 3rd anniversary, I want you to be happy, so I prepared lots of friends for you.
すっごい似合ってる！すっごい可愛い！本当だ、友達がいるから孤独じゃない！
It suits you so well! Super cute! Really, you have friends so you're not lonely!
そう、そう！本当にかわいい！え、いいの、しおんちゃん, やった！かわいい！ネットの瞬間！まあ、ありがとう！
Yeah, yeah! Really cute! Eh, is it good, Shion-chan, yay! Cute! Internet moment! Well, thank you!
うん、すごいね、さん、あたたかい気持ちになったよ！4年目もがんばるわ！
Yeah, it's amazing, I felt so warmed! I'll do my best in the 4th year too!
あ、本当に？ありがとう！あ, ほんとに? 「チャリで来た」もうさ,
Ah, really? Thank you! Ah, really? "Came by bicycle," already,
何？もうさ、私たちさ、3年も一緒にいるからさ、あの、そう、もうね、あの、トークできない！
What? Already, since we've been together for 3 years, um, yeah, we can't talk anymore!
もうなくなっちゃった！あはは！あ、もう確かに3年もね、確かに一緒にいたらなくなっちゃうよね！
It's gone! Ahaha! Ah, true, if you spend 3 years together, it really disappears!
うん、そうだね！でもね、「チャリで来た」があるからね、大丈夫だよ！「チャリで来た」のおかげで今、頭回ってる？うん、そのほうがいいと思う！じゃあ、また今度ね！写真撮れたぞ！うん、ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Yeah, that's right! But you know, since "Came by bicycle" is here, it's fine! Thanks to "Came by bicycle," is your head spinning now? Yeah, I think that's better! Well then, see you next time! Managed to take a picture! Yep, thanks! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！ありがとう！
Bye-bye! Thank you!
はいというわけで、なんかね、寂しかったなずっと、結局、え、結局、いやでも、ほら、やっぱ友達3人、あたし含め4人で今さ、4人でプリクラ撮ることなんてね？
Alright so, you know, it was kind of lonely all along, in the end, eh, in the end, no but, look, after all, three friends plus me makes four people taking purikura together now, you know?
からな ほんとに うるさかったよな チェキできた
Man, it was really noisy, wasn't it? We got the cheki!
というわけで えーと というわけでですね
Anyway, um, so anyway...
るしあちゃん お歌歌うありがとう! 今日は来てくれてありがとー!
Rushia-chan, thank you for singing! Thanks for coming today!
みんな ちゃんと写真撮った?
Did everyone take proper pictures?
え 写真撮ったかって思って シオン初めて見たからさ
I was wondering if you took pictures. Since this is your first time seeing Shion...
みんなちゃんと写真撮りまし…じゃなくて 写真撮ったみんな! よかったね
Did everyone take… I mean, did you take pictures everyone? Good for you!
あの こっちだ! これツイートしてください! 紫シオン3周年記念でね いっぱいツイートしてください!
Um, over here! Please tweet this! Tweet a lot for Murasaki Shion's 3rd anniversary!
トレンド1位になりたいな
I want to be #1 on trending.
やっぱ ほら ね? なりたいなー! なりたいなー!
I mean, you know? I want to! I really want to!
というわけで ここからはライブパートいくぞー!
And with that, from here on is the live part! Let's go!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは愛のこもった嘆き声で
My return gift will be a love-filled lament!
気のせいじゃない
It's not your imagination,
目は合ってるよ
our eyes are meeting.
ハート作って
Make a heart and
恋しちゃってください！
please fall in love with me!
やれること何でもします
I'll do whatever it takes,
NGなしで体当たり挑戦
challenging head-on with no restrictions.
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Anti-comments found through ego-surfing...
ふざけんな…誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me... I know better than anyone,
でも大丈夫ステージ(ここ)に立てばみんながいる
but it's fine, when I stand on this stage everyone is here!
(いくよ！)
(Let's go!)
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”(Fooo!!)
My return gift will be a love-filled flying kiss (Fooo!!)
虜にする！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでて愛を込めたスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！
Please also write me letters!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and make them my treasure.
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
It's still too early for a scandal,
裏切りません！宣言しときます
I won't betray you! I declare it right here.
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment,
ふざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
I'll win with my ability!
だから辞めない負けず嫌い私はいる
That's why I won't quit, I'm a sore loser and I'm here.
(いくよ！)
(Let's go!)
拳上げて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More!
汗をかいて！もっと！
Sweat more! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めたmonaビームで”(Fooo!!)
My return gift will be a love-filled mona beam (Fooo!!)
大歓声！もっと！
Huge cheers! More!
まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Still more! Hey? More!
受け入れてね愛を込めたわがままソング
Please accept my love-filled selfish song!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
はぁ…終わりが近づく
Ah... the end is approaching,
寂しいね
it's lonely, isn't it?
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though I'm having fun, I feel like crying.
次も次もまた会えるよね？(約束！)
We'll meet again next time and the time after, right? (Promise!)
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Even words overflowing with kindness,
心ない誰かの方の言葉さえも
even the heartless words of someone
必要なんだ必要なんだ強くなろう
are necessary, let's become stronger!
好きに叫べ！もっと！
Shout out your love! More!
楽しんだもん勝ち！もっと！
Enjoy yourself! More!
忘れないで特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, so that this will be a special day!
共に歌おうずずっと！共に歩もうずずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
愛言葉はとびっきりのL・O・V・E(Fooo!!)
Our password of love is an extraordinary L-O-V-E (Fooo!!)
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”(Fooo!!)
My return gift is with a love-filled flying kiss (Fooo!!)
虜にする！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでて愛を込めたスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”(Fooo!!)
My return gift will be a love-filled flying kiss (Fooo!!)
虜にする！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでて愛を込めたスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
はーい、というわけで！ありがとうございました！ファンサでした！
Hi everyone, so! Thank you very much! That was Fansa!
実はですね、みんな気づいた方もコメントをチラチラ見てたけど、いるかなーと思うのですが、
Actually, for those of you who noticed—I was glancing at the comments—I wonder if anyone caught it, but
かけ声の方ですね、あの2期生の方にお願いしました！
for the call-and-response part, I asked the 2nd Gen members!
2期生の皆さんがね、アイノテしてくれてるんだよ。ありがとう！
The 2nd Gen members did the call-and-response for me. Thank you!
そう、チョコ先生と、スバルちゃんと、アクアと、あやめちゃん。
That's right, Choco-sensei, Subaru-chan, Aqua, and Ayame-chan.
そう、そう4人だね？喋んないからね、4人だね。
That's right, four of them, right? They're not talking, so four of them, right?
そう、本当にありがとうございました！みんな気づいたかな？どう？気づいた？あっ、やっぱりって言ってる、ほら気づいたでしょ？そう、そうなんだよ。
Yeah, thank you so much! Did everyone notice? Well? Did you notice? Ah, you're saying "I knew it", see, you noticed, right? Yeah, that's right.
というわけでファンサでした！ちょっと疲れた、ちょっ、水、水飲みます。あっ、水飲みます、すいません。
And that was Fansa! I'm a bit tired, wait, water, I'll drink some water. Ah, I'm drinking water, sorry.
のど、えっすごい、ステージすごい！みんな！うぉー！
Throat—wow, amazing, the stage is amazing! Everyone! Woo!
めっちゃ紫色じゃん！紫色パレットなんだけど！
It's so purple! It's a purple palette!
というわけで、ありがとうございました！続きの曲に行きたいと思います！
And with that, thank you very much! I'd like to move on to the next song!
コン...
Kon...
ロンリー ロンリー
Lonely, lonely,
寄る辺ない侘しさに
leaning on helpless desolation,
頬杖突いてるようじゃ
resting your cheek on your hand,
変わらないわかってんだよ
it won't change, you know that.
レディメイド
Ladymade,
ありふれたモブなんだって認めてないなら
if you don't admit you're just a common mob,
いっそ腐るまで叫んで
then scream until you rot away.
異端傾げば? 赤裸々に本音ばかりじゃ生きられない
Lean toward heresy? You can't live on raw honesty alone.
路肩に寝転ぶ人生がきっとお似合いだな
A life lying face down by the roadside suits you well.
大人になれば溶け込んで金と感情で踊るのさ
Grow up and blend in, dancing with money and emotion.
1 2 3 で弾き飛んだ
Exploding on 1, 2, 3,
規定概念の間に寝転んでどうだい?どうだい?
lying between set concepts, how's that? how's that?
楽ならまっいいか レディメイドの琴線に
If it's easy, oh well—striking the heartstrings of a ladymade,
歪みかけてノイズ混ざり
warping and mixing with noise.
後悔?後悔?
Regret? Regret?
やめて黙っていてろ
Stop it and keep your mouth shut.
舌に乗った苦い感情ばかりが発火してダーティー ダーティー
Only bitter feelings on your tongue ignite, dirty, dirty.
言葉飲み込めばほら
Swallow your words and see,
いい子になるわなんてさ
"I'll be a good girl," you say,
顔色窺ってんだよ
reading everyone's expressions.
ベイビー
Baby.
デタラメ デタラメ
Nonsense, nonsense,
言葉飲み込めばほら
swallow your words and see,
ヒーローになるわよなんて顔色伺ってんだよ
"I'll be a hero," you say, reading expressions.
レディメイド
Ladymade,
歪みだすラブなんだって
a love that's distorting,
オーダーメイドのブランド身に付けて威張って
strutting around in custom-made brands,
下を鳴らせばケスバリと
clicking your tongue raspily,
不出来ごんしゃま魔女狩りさ
a clumsy witch hunt.
鼻垂れ泥棒人生がきったお似合いだな
A runny-nosed thief's life surely suits you.
社会の外側はどうそうぜいか
What is outside of society anyway?
金も愛情もクソ喰らえ
To hell with money and love.
1 2 3 で弾き飛んだ
Exploding on 1, 2, 3,
規定概念の間に寝転んで
lying between set concepts.
ワンツーすりいで弾き飛んだ
Exploding on one, two, three,
規定概念の間に寝転んで
lying between set concepts,
どうだい?どうだい? なくならないか
how's that? how's that? Won't it disappear?
レディメイドの金銭に
Striking the finances of a ladymade,
歪みかけてノイズ弾き飛んだ
warping and sending noise flying,
問題?問題? 統括だって詰め込んで
problem? problem? packing it up as an overview.
黒い感情ばかりが発火して ダーティー ダーティー
Only dark emotions ignite, dirty, dirty.
言葉飲み込めばほら いい子になるわなんてさ
Swallow your words and see, "I'll be a good girl," you say,
顔色窺ってんだよ ベイビー
reading everyone's expressions, baby.
甘えちゃいけないの放っといて 私あたしにしかいないの
"You mustn't spoil yourself," leave me alone, I'm the only one who has myself.
1 2 3 で弾き飛んだ
Exploding on 1, 2, 3,
規定概念の間に寝転んで
lying between set concepts,
大人になれば溶け込んで
growing up and blending in,
金と愛情で本当のさ
dancing with money and love.
ワンツーすりいで弾き飛んだ 規定概念の間に寝転んで
Exploding on one, two, three, lying between set concepts,
どうだい?どうだい? なくならないか
how's that? how's that? Won't it disappear?
レディメイドの金銭に 歪みかけてノイズ弾き飛んだ
Striking the finances of a ladymade, warping and sending noise flying.
聞き飽きた
Sick of hearing it,
世界の真ん中に立って
standing in the middle of the world,
ないものねだり
crying for things I can't have,
本当は泣いていた
when I was actually crying.
レディメイドのエンブレムに
With a readymade emblem,
ゲートかけてノイズ弾き飛んだ
putting up a gate and bouncing off the noise.
問題問題、統括だっていの
Problem after problem, even supervision is...
下手に乗った苦い感情ばかりが加速して
Only bitter emotions poorly ridden accelerate.
やんないじゃないできないんだ
It's not that I won't do it, I can't!
ダダダダ天使
[Title: Dadadada Angel]
あの時間この空間で噂のダテ天使
In that time and space, the rumored date angel
ダメなところはモーテンシー
my blind spots where I fail are...
生方はあがなっていく
Atoning for my birth as I go,
その予感さあ
that premonition, come on!
もう足りないのもっともっとあなたに気にしてほしい
I'm still not satisfied, I want you to notice me more.
だけど注目されすぎたらビビる急速コンピュート
But if I get too much attention, my rapid computer freaks out.
天使のリングの熱滅は色褪げてるけど味方をかえればこれもうアーピーディーサ
The angel ring's fever is fading, but from another angle, this is already RPD.
なんて強がりさ本当は曖昧な愛の感情もあなたと探したいの
What a bluff, actually I want to search for even ambiguous feelings of love with you.
ねえダメダメダメダメなアタシを
Hey, love me, me who is no good at all,
愛してね
love me!
災害の衝動に向けるオタク
Otaku turning toward impulses of disaster,
天使ですがドキドキドキドキドキを上げるよ
I'm an angel, but I'll make your heart race!
あなたにはちゃんと見ていてくれるなら
If you'll properly look at me,
やるよたぶんダンダンダンダンダメ天使は
I'll do it, maybe, dan dan dan dan, this useless angel.
だがしかしアタシはいいかやんないじゃないできないんだ
But however, I... it's not that I won't do it, I can't!
ベストで一点取りたいでも頭がちっともういつかない
I want to get a top score, but my brain can't keep up at all.
日曜日だって早起きしたい
I want to wake up early even on Sundays.
深夜の寝言がやめられないんだやりたくないとかそんなんじゃないやりたくてもできないしもうしょうがないなって
I can't stop talking in my sleep at night, it's not that I don't want to do it, I can't even if I want to, so it can't be helped.
許してよエンゼルリングをほばりながらこんなアタシに誰がしたんだってこんなアタシにアタシがしたのかしょうがないなって
Forgive me, while stuffing the angel ring, who did this to me? Did I do this to myself? Oh well.
天使の翼は使ってない飛ぶの怖いから
I'm not using my angel wings because flying is scary,
本気を出したら飛べますかみたいな顔をしている
making a face like 'I could fly if I got serious'.
そんな針を手の裏側に隠した愛の感情が
Such feelings of love with needles hidden on the back of my hand
あなたに笑ってほしいの
I want you to smile at me.
ねえダメダメダメダメなアタシでいいですか
Hey, is it okay if I'm a no-good me?
実際は一切の自信もないような天使ですが
Actually I'm an angel with zero confidence at all, but
グルグルグルグルと巡る頭の中ではあなたのことばかり考えてるんだ
spinning around and around in my head, I'm thinking only about you.
ダメダメダメダメなアタシを愛してよ
Love me, a no-good me!
もらった愛とずっともうよ
Forever with the love I received,
天使だからドキドキドキドキドキを上げるよ
because I'm an angel, I'll make your heart race!
あなたにはもっと好きになってくれるなら
If you'll come to like me even more,
やるよたぶんダンダンダンダンダメ天使は
I'll do it, maybe, dan dan dan dan, this useless angel.
だがしかしアタシはいいかやんないじゃないできないんだ
But however, I... it's not that I won't do it, I can't!
やだでも努力はします
No, but I'll make an effort!
はい、というわけでちょっとね途中からねイヤホンが取れちゃったけど頑張って最後まで歌いました！
So, um, halfway through, my earphone came off, but I tried my best and sang all the way to the end!
はい、というわけでみんなダダダダ天使でした。その一個前の曲がレディメイドでした。というわけで二曲通してありがとうございました！
So everyone, that was Dadadada Angel. And the song right before that was Readymade. So thank you very much for listening to both songs!
続いてはですね皆さんえ、重大発表とはなんだろうと思ってるんじゃないですか！？
Next, everyone... aren't you wondering what the major announcement is?!
なんと今ここで1つ目の重大告知をしたいと思います！イエーイ！
And now, I'd like to make my first major announcement! Yay!
なんとこの度紫咲シオン初の
And this time, Murasaki Shion's very first...
じゃーん！オリジナル曲出ます！イエーイ！みんな待ってたのではなかろうか、どーん！
ta-da! Original song is coming out! Yay! Have you all been waiting for this? Ba-dum!
はい、「メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット」という曲です。えー、この曲はですね、かいりきベアさんに書き下ろしていただきましたの。
Yes, it's a song called "Meiji of Violet." Um, this song was written for me by Kairiki Bear-san.
の、本当にね、かいりきベアさんの曲全部かわいくて大好きなんですよ。だから書き下ろしてもらえてとても嬉しいです。
Really, all of Kairiki Bear-san's songs are so cute and I love them. So I'm super happy they wrote one for me.
イラストはかいりきベアさんの曲と言ったら、のう先生、みたいなのあるんじゃないでしょうか？のう先生にですね、描いてもらいました。
For the illustrations, when you think of Kairiki Bear-san's songs, you think of Nou-sensei, right? Nou-sensei drew them for me.
ちょっと息が切れてる（笑）はい。
I'm running out of breath. Haha! Yes.
というわけで、みなさんのちょっとちょっと水飲んでいいですか？ちょっと告知のターンなんですけど。
So anyway, everyone, can I drink some water for a second? This is the announcement part, though.
はい、というわけでこの後ですね、歌うんですが、えー、この後の22時配信終わりの22時2部に、プレミアの公開として、歌とMVが公開されます！
Right, so after this, I'm going to sing, but at 22:00, right after the stream ends, at 22:02, the song and MV will premiere!
みんなそちらも絶対見てくださいね！本当に絶対ですよ！今見てる人全員見てくださいね！はーい（笑）
Everyone, please be sure to watch that too! Really, absolutely! Everyone watching right now, be sure to watch it! Haha!
というわけで、えーそろそろですね、行きたいと思います！オリジナル曲の「メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット」です！
So, it's about time to go! My original song, "Meiji of Violet"!
メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット 作詞・作曲：かいりきベア 編曲：すりぃ
[Title: Meiji of Violet / Lyrics & Music: Kairiki Bear / Arrangement: Three]
暗い方ばっか見てないで
Don't keep looking only at the dark side,
ウラパッパッパパラリラ踊れよ
Ura-pa-pa-pa-paralira, dance away!
魔界学校の優等生
Honor student of the demon school,
華やかな我が魔力讃えよ
praise my magnificent magic!
イナイナイばぁ！でこっち向いて
Inai-nai-ba! Look this way,
華やかな未来を咲かせよ
make a vibrant future bloom!
次第相殺って高まって
Gradually neutralizing, rising,
溜め込んだMP放て
release the stored MP!
黒魔術定の刻に集えよ
Gather at the appointed hour of dark arts,
闇に震えるケルベロス
you Cerberus trembling in the dark!
切に響く言葉はブチギレ発狂パラダイス
Words echoing earnestly are a snapping, mad paradise,
キラリココロ奥底まで届け
shining deep into my heart!
これからも私の下で不思議な力打ち放て
From now on too, under my command, unleash strange powers,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
making the whole world smile too!
ウラパッパッパパラリラ歌えば
Ura-pa-pa-pa-paralira, if you sing,
一生一緒だよね
it's together forever, right?
暗い方ばっかしてないで
Don't keep downcast like that,
生またからどっさらば踊れよ
since you were born, goodbye and dance away!
視界外目逸らさないで
Don't look away from my field of view,
今はただ離れてかないで
right now, just don't leave my side!
いやいや待ってあっち向いて
No, no, wait, look over there,
今はまだ心の準備を
right now you still need to prepare your heart,
期待遮って固まって
blocking expectations, freezing up,
ウラパッパッパ動きくろまじゅつ
Ura-pa-pa-pa, moving black magic!
われに続け今宵よ
Follow me tonight,
闇を裂けメシアよ
tear the darkness apart, O Messiah!
朽ちべきものその名は
The name of the perishable being is
眠りの端よパラダイス
the edge of sleep, paradise!
キラリココロ奥底まで届け
Shine deep into my heart,
白黒つけてあげるから
because I'll settle things in black and white!
不思議な力振りかざして
Brandishing mysterious powers,
みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
making everyone smile!
ウラパッパッパパラリラ歌えば
Ura-pa-pa-pa-paralira, if you sing,
一生一緒かもね
maybe it's together forever!
左ひらりと紫色に染まって
Fluttering left, dyed in purple,
これからもあなたのもとで
from now on too, by your side,
奇跡の呪文解き放って
unleashing the spell of miracles,
咲かせる笑顔の花を
making the flower of smiling faces bloom!
キラリココロ奥底まで届け
Shine deep into my heart,
これからも変わらないままで
staying unchanged from now on too!
不思議な力ほら宿って
Look, mysterious power dwells within,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
making the world smile too!
ウラパッパッパパラリラ歌えば
Ura-pa-pa-pa-paralira, if you sing,
一生一緒だよね
it's together forever, right?
絶対一緒だよね
Definitely together forever, right?
めちゃめちゃ素敵な曲だと思うんですが、どうでしょうか
I think it's a really wonderful song, but what do you think?
皆さんいかがでしょうか
How are you all doing?
この後ですね、MVも公開されるのでよかったら見てください。
After this, the MV will be released, so please check it out if you'd like.
よかったらじゃねえよ、絶対見ろよ！
What do you mean "if you'd like"? You definitely have to watch it!
はい、というわけで、あの22時からですね、プレミアム公開の枠、実際ハテナハテナハテナで立てさせていただいたんですが、
Yes, so, starting at 22:00, we set up the premiere frame with question marks,
それがオリジナル曲のMVのプレミアム公開の枠となっております。
and that turned out to be the premiere frame for the original song's MV.
見てね、絶対見てよ！
Watch it, make sure you watch it!
はい、というわけで、告知第2！
Yes, so, announcement number two!
なんと、3周年記念グッズ、イエーイ！
And now, 3rd anniversary goods, yay!
みんなね、多分きっと気づいてたと思うけど、
Everyone probably already noticed, but
3周年記念グッズがでます！
the 3rd anniversary goods are coming out!
あの、
Um,
と いうわけでですね、あの、活動3周年記念ということで、8月17日今日！
so, as a commemoration for the 3rd anniversary, today, August 17th,
このあとですね、発売されます。えーと概要欄にですね多分あのURLも貼ってある と思うので、ぜひそちらから皆さんあの、このあと見てください。
it goes on sale after this. The URL should be in the description, so please check it out.
記念グッズ3種ということで、えーまず、
As for the 3 types of commemorative goods, first,
ブランケット！
the blanket!
はい、ブランケットと、紫シオンのボイス入り目覚まし時計。
Yes, the blanket, and Murasaki Shion's voice-included alarm clock.
いや もこれ後程あの、詳しく説明しますんで。ランダムアクリルキーホルダーが1種ということで、これがフルセットですね。
I'll explain this later. And one type of random acrylic keychain, which makes up the full set.
とりあえずじゃあ、ブランケットから見ていこうと思います。
So first, let's take a look at the blanket.
どうぞ。
Here it is.
はい、ででーん！
Ta-da!
はい、なんとイラストはTam-U先生、しかもママが描き下ろし た新しいイラストを描いてくれました。かわいい！
The illustration is by Tam-U-sensei, and mama drew a brand new illustration for us. So cute!
あの、ですねブランケットの方 は、あの大きいから、フルルのね、あのイラストを全部写ってる。すごい！かわいいです。全部写ってるからね、あの、目覚まし時計の方は切り取られてるんですけど。
Since the blanket is big, all of the illustration is captured. It's so cute!
そう、めちゃめちゃかわいいんだよ、これ。
Yes, it's super cute, this.
なんと皆さんお気づきの通り、コンセプトは睡眠です！
As you all probably noticed, the concept is sleep!
コンセプトは睡眠。えーなんでですかね、本当に。
The concept is sleep. Why is that, really?
なんで睡眠なんですかね。なんかね、シオンといえば寝ろみたいなよくない噂が、噂が立っておりますけどね。
Why is it sleep? Rumors like "Shion, go to sleep" are going around, though.
はい、というわけで、ブランケットね、めちゃめちゃかわいいし、あのめちゃめちゃ大きいので、あの、ぜひ皆さんこれも手に入れてください。
The blanket is super cute and huge, so I hope you'll all get your hands on it.
はい、次、どーん！
Okay, next, boom!
はい、紫シオンのボイス入り目覚まし時計。
Yes, Murasaki Shion's voice-included alarm clock.
これです皆さん、これすごいから本当に！
This is it, everyone, this is really amazing!
これはですね、オリジナルボイス5種類収録しました！
This has 5 types of original voices recorded!
え、取り下ろしました、あの5種類ですね、この目覚まし時計のために。
We recorded 5 types fresh, specifically for this alarm clock.
え、実これ、あの、なるじゃないですか、目覚まし時計って。それ、シオンの声なんです！
Actually, you know how alarm clocks ring? Well, that's Shion's voice!
シオンの声で朝が迎えれるという、え、素晴らしいものとなっております。
You can be greeted in the morning by Shion's voice, which is wonderful.
色もね、かわいいよね、紫色で、なんかちょっと甘い感じの パステル紫色みたいな色でとてもかわいいのではないでしょうか。
The color is also cute, a sweet pastel purple, which is super cute.
え、これですでに、あの、仕事に行く方も、学生の方も、これ で毎朝起きていただけたら、
Whether you're going to work or are a student, if you wake up to this every morning,
なんといい目覚めをね、迎えれるか。あの、起きてください、本当に。最高ですよね、こんなこと。
what a great awakening you'll have! Please wake up to it. Isn't this the best?
はい、というわけで、5種類あるのでですね、ランダムで再生されます。多分。
Since there are 5 types, they play at random. Probably.
ランダムで再生されると思います。これめちゃめちゃすごいから！
I think they play randomly. This is super amazing!
みんな手に入れてください。これもイラストはTam-U先生です。
Please get it. The illustration is also by Tam-U-sensei.
かわいいよね、これ。最高でしょ？最高なんだよ！
It's cute, right? Isn't it the best? It's the best!
はい、次、でん！
Okay, next, ta-da!
はい、ランダムアクリルキーホルダー1種（全4種）ということで、
Random acrylic keychains, 1 type (4 variations total).
これですね、むーらん先生がイラストを描いてくれました。4種類あります。
Muran-sensei drew the illustrations. There are 4 kinds.
これ実はシオンがちょっとやってみたかったことで、今回、あの、やらせていただきました。あの、ありがとうございます、はい。
Actually, this was something Shion wanted to try, so we got to do it. Thank you!
ランダムの、アクリルキーホルダー、まあめちゃめちゃそのままだないか。ランダムのアクリルキーホルダーなんですけど、
They are random acrylic keychains,
イラストがですね、通常衣装とアイドル衣装と、あと、これも通常衣装なん ですけど、上にですね、しおっこがいるんです。
with illustrations of a normal outfit, an idol outfit, and a normal outfit with little Shiokko.
これみんなのことですね。あの、これむーらん先生がシオンのリスナーさんのことを、あの、イメージ
That refers to all of you. Muran-sensei imagined Shion's listeners
キャラクターを作ってくれたから、今回むーらん先生にですね、あの、お 願いして、
and created characters for them, so we asked Muran-sensei
あの、イラストを描き下ろしていただきました。ありがとうございます。
to draw these new illustrations. Thank you very much.
あとゴスロリ衣装！これはかわいい猫ちゃん。にゃー。
And the gothic lolita outfit! This cute kitty. Meow.
はい、むーらん先生がですね、担当してます。ということで、こちらもぜひ皆さん、あの全部揃えてください。あの、揃える とは言いませんが、揃えてください、ぜひ。
Muran-sensei is in charge. Please collect all of them, definitely.
はい、というわけで、以上がフルセットの内容となっております。
Yes, so that covers the contents of the full set.
というわけで、フルセット購入特典として、Tam-U先生描き下ろしポストカードがついてきます！
So, as a full-set purchase bonus, a Tam-U-sensei postcard is included!
はーい、イエーイ！
Hi, yay!
えー、今回はですね、あの前回の誕生日のときはね、
Uh, this time, um, last time for my birthday,
箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードということで、
it's a postcard with a foil-stamped replica signature and message,
メッセージの方は届いてからのお楽しみとなっています！
and the message part will be a surprise after it arrives!
これを全部買うよね、みんな。
You're all gonna buy all of these, right?
全部買うでしょ？全部買って、見てください、飾ってください、一緒に！
Buy all of them, right? Buy them all and look at them, display them together!
よろしくお願いします！かわいいでしょ？
Please look forward to it! Cute, right?
キラキラなんだよ！サインとメッセージが！はい！
It's sparkly! The signature and the message! Yes!
というわけで、以上の、えー、3つ、3つとは考えがたいぐらいのボリュームだけど、
So, those are the, uh, three goods—well, it's so much volume it's hard to think of it as just three,
そう、ポストカード抜いて3つの、えー、グッズでした。
excluding the postcard, those three goods.
これね、みんな絶対に手に入れてください。概要欄からどうぞよろしくお願いします！
Everyone, definitely get your hands on these. Check the description box, please!
というわけで、この後ですね、あの、すぐ、すぐっていうか、
So, after this, um, right away—well, right away, as in
あの今、9時52分ということで、この後22時から、オリジナル曲のMVが公開されます！
it's currently 9:52—starting at 22:00, the MV for my original song will be released!
絶対！絶対見てください！本当にかん、一生のお願いをここで使うかもしれないぐらいのお願いですので、お願いします！
Definitely! Definitely watch it! It's an earnest request, like I might even use a lifetime favor right here, so please!
はい、ということで、メイジ・オブ・バイオレット！
Yes, so, "Mage of Violet"!
ぜひね、見てください。素敵に仕上がっておりますので。
Please check it out, everyone. It turned out wonderfully.
はい、ということで、みんな今日は、Shionのね、3周年を祝っていただいて、ありがとうございました。
So, everyone, thank you so much for celebrating Shion's 3rd anniversary today.
思ったより早く終わっちゃったね。ちょっと、Shionが早口で喋りすぎたわ。
It ended a bit faster than I thought. Ah, Shion talked way too fast.
みんなありがとね！コメントちゃんと見えてるからね！みんなよろしくだよ！グッズの、おりきょくもたくさん聴くし、グッズもすぐ購入する、はい、よろしくお願いします！
Thank you everyone! I can see your comments properly! Please treat me well, everyone! Listen to the original songs a lot, buy the goods right away, yes, please!
ということで、3周年ありがとうございました！
So, thank you so much for the 3rd anniversary!
4周年の紫咲シオンもどうぞよろしくお願いします！
Please continue to support Murasaki Shion in her 4th year as well!
これからも頑張りまーす！みんなありがとう！
I'll keep doing my best! Thank you everyone!
じゃあね、バイバーイ！
See ya, bye-bye!